# **DANIEL STANLEY**

4452 Redfern Place Winston-Salem NC 27107 | 336-682-9091

danielclays@yahoo.com | www.linkedin.com/pub/daniel-stanley/25/475/a12

## **PROFILE**

Working towards surrounding myself in a career that is exciting, challenging, and rewarding with a well-established work place offering ample opportunities for growth and further career advancement while surrounding myself with good people.

I am a jack of all trades type with experience in advertising/project management, architectural design/ drafting, retail/operations management, health and fitness, and professional motorsports/auto racing research and development as well as pit crew duties in both open wheel and stock car disciplines just to scratch the surface.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

ELECTRONIC PART DATABASE MANAGER & TECHNICAL WRITER, NASCAR; CONCORD NC - 2013

- -Position requires thorough knowledge of all parts and components both Vendor and Team manufactured and how they function on the race car
- -Position requires thorough knowledge of said parts adhering to the NASCAR Rulebook specifications to become an approved part
- -Ability to read and understand engineering drawings, CAD, and rapid part prototypes(plastic) of newly developed team/vendor parts.
- -Project Managing the development, formalization, and implementation of the new Part Submission and Specification Change Request Process
- -Project Managing the development of a real time industry-accessible (120+ Part Vendors / 85+ Race Teams), centralized, interactive proprietary parts database software (app) for all submitted parts
- Project Managing the development of a real time industry-accessible(120+ Part Vendors / 85+ Race Teams), centralized, interactive digital Rule Book.
- -Creating/organizing and warehousing an in-house inventory of Vendor submitted parts, Team submitted parts, and NASCAR seized parts to be implemented into proprietary parts database software(app)
- -Assisting with development, formalization, and implementation of the new Digital Rulebook 2.0(app)
- -Coordination of software development, CAD drawings, and rulebook language/technical specifications timelines to meet project deadlines
- -Communicate daily with external vendors, teams, and OEM's
- -Create spreadsheets, PP Presentations, etc. for part/data research meetings and presentations

SCHEDULING & TRAFFICKING SPECIALIST, LOWE'S CORPORATE HQ; MOORESVILLE, NC -- 2013

- 8 week contract work assignment
- -Assess Marketing, Advertising, and Communications project requests and identify and assemble relevant project partner participants based on business needs.
- -Handle the creation, maintenance, and execution of schedules and prioritize deadlines using IBM's UNICA project management software.
- -Participate in cross-functional meetings, including weekly production meetings. Recording and publishing meeting notes to the team.
- -Executions include: Print, Circulars, In-store Collateral/POS, Internal Communications/Brochures, Employee Training Materials/BTV, OOH, DM, Web, etc.

# IZOD INDYCAR SERIES FUELER, PENSKE RACING; MOORESVILLE, NC -- 2013

- Fueler for a part time effort for the 2013 season. Over the wall pit crew member assisting with all pit practice and equipment maintenance duties. Assist with all at track activities and perform all Tire Specialist's duties.

PROJECT MANAGER & ASSISTANT ART/MEDIA BUYER, MULLEN; WINSTON-SALEM, NC -- 2010-2012

- -Managing local, national, and global account implementation, execution and maintenance of project plans that identify key milestones, project dependencies, and project resources.
- -Prepare materials for account teams for all client meetings
- -Participate in all creative concepting for existing, as well as new business clients.
- Creative, design, pre-press and production skills used daily due to high print volume accounts.
- -Oversee day-to-day internal and external communications regarding project status and timelines.
- Executions include: Print, Direct Mail, OOH, TV, OLA (including HTML, e-mail, Web banners, website development), Social, etc.
- -Responsible for the negotiation, purchase, and production details of all print, direct mail, interactive and broadcast advertising visuals involving: Photography, illustration, stock imagery/footage, digital image creation and retouching.

CAD DRAFTSMAN, PHIL'S DESIGN INC; CLEMMONS, NC -- 2006-2009

http://www.northcarolinaresidentialdesign.com/

-Responsible for the design and production/assembly of residential house plans using

ArchiCAD/PlotMaker softwares

-Responsible for meeting with customers/builders on site as well as office meetings to ensure

customer/builder satisfaction

OPERATIONS MANAGER, SPORTS AUTHORITY; WINSTON-SALEM, NC -- 1999-2006

Positions held:

-Sales Associate I & II: Apparel, Footwear, Team Sports, & Outdoors

-Team Lead: Footwear, Team Sports, & Outdoors

-MasterTech: Responsible for building all display equipment: BB Goals, Building and servicing Bikes,

Fitness Equipment, etc. Responsible for being certified to string and tension tennis racquets, size, drill, and

sand bowling balls, drill, mount, and service ski/snowboard bindings.

-Operations Manager: Responsible for all Human Resources, Audits, Safety Inspections, Hiring/

Firing, Scheduling/Vacations, Cash Office, Opening/Closing store, Corporate visits, etc.

## **EDUCATION**

PIT Performance Instruction & Training -- 2005

Certificate of Performance, PIT Crew U / 5 Off 5 On Program Class #51

-Pit Crew U is the experiential education division of Performance Instruction & Training designed to teach the specific skills associated with a career as an over-the-wall pit crew team member in stock car motorsports. The program is both physically and mentally challenging and provides a level of skill development that exceeds"understanding the concepts." Persons who successfully complete the program have both the knowledge and the skills to actually perform and put to action the concepts.

- Trained w/ RCR developmental team 2008 & 2012
- Trained with Drivers Support Team(DST) and former RCR pit crew coaches from 2006-2008
- 2013 Developmental IZOD IndyCar Series Fueler

Forsyth Technical College; Winston-Salem, NC -- 2004 AAS Architecture / CAD

Referrals and References available upon request.